postgrad.com 2019-01-27

# Privacy Policy for Postgrad Solutions Ltd | Postgrad.com

Postgrad.com is owned by Postgrad Solutions and aims to provide the best portal for students looking for information on postgraduate-related courses taught in English anywhere around the globe. Postgrad.com is committed to safeguarding the personal information you provide to us and to protect your privacy. By submitting your personal information to any of our websites, you are confirming that you have read and understood how we may use your personal information provided by you.

**1\. Collecting Personal Information**

We collect personal information about you when you register with us through our

(i) Electronic registration forms on [Postgrad.com](https://www.postgrad.com/) and [LLMstudy.com](https://www.llmstudy.com/). (NB If you sign up for Postgrad.com on the subject of Law you may also receive information from our sister site LLMstudy.com).

(ii) Through completing a [survey](https://www.postgrad.com/survey/closed/).

(iii) When you apply for one of our [Postgrad Solutions Study Bursaries](https://www.postgrad.com/fees_and_funding/postgrad_solutions_study_bursaries/information/).

(iv) When you comment on one of our blogs. Although only your name will be shown on the public-facing website, the name and email address you enter with your comment will be saved to our database, along with your computer’s IP address and the time and date that you submitted the comment. This information is only used to identify you as a contributor to the comment section of the blog post and is not passed on to any of the third party data processors detailed below in section 5.0. Your comment and its associated personal data will remain on our site until we see fit to either 1.) Remove the comment or 2.) Remove the blog post. Should you wish to have the comment and its associated personal data deleted, please contact us.

Please do not add a comment on our blog if you are under 16 years of age.

**2\. Site Visitation Tracking**

In addition to your personal information when you register, when you use our website we also collect tracking information such as your browser type, the type of operating system you use, your IP address, and pages visited on the site. This information helps us increase the user-friendliness of our website and to better tailor our website to your needs. We use cookies and Google Analytics to track user interaction, to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how people find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website. We consider Google to be a third party data processor (see section 5.0 below).

**3\. How The Information Is Used**

We collect the personal information you supplied in section 1.0 so that we can send you tailor-made information on postgraduate products that will be of interest to you. You will be updated regularly throughout the year with our newsletters and e-shots – and each time we communicate with you there will be the opportunity to unsubscribe.

We collect information for the following purposes:

\- To reply to your enquiries more efficiently through the services we provide.

\- To send you news items, including information on postgraduate courses you might be interested in by email. (NB If you sign up for Postgrad.com on the subject of Law you may also receive information from our sister site LLMstudy.com).

\- To inform you of new offers, products and services that may be of interest to you by email.

\- To conduct market research by email.

**4\. Sharing Information With Our University Clients**

We may share specific parts of member information with our university clients. The reasons we do this are as follows:

  * To manage our relationship with advertisers to help prove that relevant students are consistently using our sites.
  * To highlight to universities that respondents to our survey have stated they have applied or intend to apply to their university or a similar university if this information is completed in the survey data.
  * To check if a student bursary application qualifies for one of our bursaries, as student needs to have started a course at university to qualify.

**NB Your email address will NEVER be communicated to a third party (except for our third party data processors detailed in section 5.0.) The university will only be sent your name, nationality and course of interest. _They will not be able to contact you directly from this limited top level information._**

We also provide some top level information to our clients with regards to the generic profile of people who have signed up to our database, eg average age, gender and nationality. Our database exceeds 30,000+ people, this information is not used to create any individual profiling, we will only provide generic statistics about the type of people using our website. It cannot be linked to an individual’s details.

**  5\. Third Party Data Processors**

We use a number of third parties to collect and process personal data on our behalf. These third parties have been carefully chosen and all of them comply with data regulations.

The third party data processors we use are:

•          Google ([Privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB))

•          Wildfish ([Privacy policy](https://wildfish.com/privacy/))

We may also store data from time to time on Microsoft systems including Sharepoint ([Privacy policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-GB/))

**6\. Strict Not Sharing Policy**

We will **never share your email address** details with third parties (excluding our third party data processors detailed in section 5.0). We NEVER sell our data or give access to it to anyone else so no one else will contact you. All direct communication comes from Postgrad.com and Postgrad Solutions Ltd. 

From time to time we may share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to this site to business partners such as the number of users we have, their average age, location, etc. This information will be shared in a way that ensures your identity is not revealed.

We may also disclose or access your account if required to do so by law or any other governmental body.

**7\. Lawful Basis For Collecting Data**

Postgrad.com and Postgrad Solutions Ltd lawful basis for processing personal data complies with Article 6 of the GDPR categories:

(a) Consent: and (f) Legitimate interests.

**8\. Security of Personal Information Against Cyber Attacks & Breaches**

Our technical services provider holds all student data on their servers to process this information, however they do not use it.

Although we use HTTPS connections to encrypt and protect your information, sending data over the internet is not completely secure, so we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information while it’s in transit. Once we receive your personal information our technical services provider has procedures and security features in place to ensure that it is protected against cyber attacks and potential breaches.

Additionally, from time to time, records may need to be sent by email that may not be encrypted. We will nonetheless do our utmost to protect your data as far as we can. We take our data protection extremely seriously.

**9\. Links From Our Websites**

Our websites contain links to other websites, which are not controlled by Postgrad.com and Postgrad Solutions Ltd. This Privacy Statement applies only to our sites. Please note if you click on a banner advertisement, the click may take you off our website.

**10\. Unsubscribing & Removing your Postgrad Solutions Data**

You can unsubscribe from our email services by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any of our email communication to you. This will also remove your personal data associated with our email service.

If you have previously submitted a bursary application or participated in our surveys, we may still hold some of the information you provided even after you unsubscribe from our emails. If you would like us to fully remove your information please contact us with your request at [datamanager@postgradsolutions.com](mailto:datamanager@postgradsolutions.com) including your full name and email address.  We will ensure that it is removed in line with GDPR policies and timescales on request.

**11\. Privacy Policy Changes**

If our privacy policy changes significantly we will contact you by email and advise you what has changed. This email will contain an unsubscribe link like all our other email correspondence giving you the option to opt out.

Privacy Policy: Last modified May 2018.
